Guide to the Carlingford Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Later Carlingford Papers, Dates 1670-1764; Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  - NICHOLAS TAAFFE (d. 1691), 2ND EARL OF CARLINGFORD, PAPERS
    - Clanricarde, William Bourke, 7th Earl of, d. 1687.
      - LS to the Earl of Carlingford, Portumna, 1677/8 Jan 8 (Box 4, Folder 94)
        Also signed by Lucas Dillon, 1st Viscount Dillon, d. 1682, and Piers Butler, 3rd Viscount of Galmoye, 1652-1740. Concerning the 1st Earl of Carlingford's death.
  - FRANCIS TAAFFE (1639-1704), 3RD EARL OF CARLINGFORD, PAPERS
    - Letters from Francis Taaffe
      - AL to Theobald, Earl of Carlingford, from a camp in Hungary., 1670 Jun 20 (Box 4, Folder 95)
        Discusses military effort to suppress rebellion in Hungary.
      - AL, draft, to Theobald, Earl of Carlingford, Ulm, 1675 Feb 7 [n.s.] (Box 4, Folder 96)
        "Tis near a twelvemonth since I have heard a word from yr Lordship..." Taaffe sends news to his father about his activities in military campaigns.
      - AL, draft, to [Nicholas Taaffe], Siege of Philipsburg, [1676 Jul 13] (Box 4, Folder 97)
        Prince Pio has offered the command of a regiment to Francis Taaffe.
      - ALS to Henry Coventry, D'Eslingen en Shwabe, 1677 Feb 26 [n.s.] (Box 4, Folder 98)
        Reports that he has been given command of the Duke of Lorraine's regiment. Lorraine's marriage with the Queen of Poland is off. Affairs of the Empire.
      - AL, draft, to [Nicholas Taaffe], Ratisbone, 1678 Jan 21[n.s.] (Box 4, Folder 99)
        Marriage of Lorraine to Queen of Poland. Attempts to bring the French towards peace.
      - 8 AL, drafts, to unnamed recipients, various places in Europe, 1676 Jul 13-1680 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 100)
        News of the siege of Philippsbourg; events after the Battle of Saverne; words of praise for the Duke of Lor- raine's giving him command of a regiment; reaction to his father's death; need of English support for Emperor against France.
      - ALS (draft) to James, Duke of York, later James II, King of England, 1633- 1704, [1684] (Box 4, Folder 101)
        Addressed to "Monseigneur," the letter describes in detail the campaign of 1684 in which the Imperial armies were driven back from the siege of Buda.
    - Other Papers
      - ALS from "Charles" to M. de Henckelman, Osnabrug, 1704 Aug 21 (Box 4, Folder 102)
        Concerning the death of Francis Taaffe, Earl of Carlingford
      - Charles II, King of Great Britain, LS to Ferdinand III, in Latin, Bruges, 1656 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 103)
        Thanks him for his favor to Francis Taaffe, who was at this time Page of Honor in the Emperor's service.
  - NICHOLAS TAAFFE (1677-1769), 6TH VISCOUNT TAAFFE, PAPERS
    - Joseph Emmanuel, King of Portugal, 1733- 1765. Letter, copy, to the Emperor of Germany, Ajuda concerning Nicholas, 6th Viscount Taaffe., 1764 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 104)
- Curatorial Files, Series IV
  - Curator's Files, circa 1990s (Box 5)